Sai Manideep Chittiprolu

Greensboro, NC (27403) • +1 (980) 895-5999 • saimanideep83@gmail.com • LinkedIn

Summary

Python Developer with 2+ years of experience programming pythons. Focused professional recognized by peers for my effective analytical and critical thinking skills. Seeking a challenging career with the opportunity to learn more in an organization with a positive growth-oriented work environment.

Education

Master of Science in computer science

University of North Carolina at Greensboro - Greensboro, NC

2022 - present

Relevant Coursework: Data Science, Big Data and Machine Learning, Digital Image Processing, Advanced Database Systems and Database System Architecture, Natural language Processing, GPA-3.6

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication Engineering

R.V.R & J.C. College of Engineering, Guntur, AP, India, GPA – 3.2

2016 - 2020

Professional Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

2021 - present

UNC Greensboro, Greensboro, NC

- Identified and documented details of business rules, Data Modeling, Data Analytics, Data Science using Python.
- Hands-on experience in the design, construction, testing and tuning of a research network built using Science DMX model developed by ES Network.
- Implementation using new tools like Globus API to transmit vast amounts of data with network security.

Python Developer 2020 – 2021

Infosys Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, Telangana, India

- Development and implementation for Medtronic MyCase Application with the Python programming language. Analyzing user requirements and designing solutions that meet their demands.
- Developed and maintained ETL pipelines to transfer and transform data from various sources into Apache Spark.
- Participating in agile software development practices including stand-up meetings, sprint planning, and retrospectives
- Derive rapid resolution of all issues related to SAP processes, coordinating all involved teams.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, SQL
- Front End Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Frameworks: Pandas, NumPy, Scikit Learn, Matplotlib, React JS
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Tomcat, Jupyter Notebook, Eclipse, Anaconda, Jira
- Others: Apache Spark, Agile, Tableau, GitHub, Advanced MS Excel, SAP SD

Academic Projects

Early Drowsy detection Using Machine Learning

- Driver drowsiness detection is an important function in a vehicle. Drowsy driving is a serious risk to road safety and detecting driver drowsiness is therefore important for safe driving. This project, however, focuses on driver drowsiness detection using machine learning techniques.
- Tools: NumPy, OpenCV, Pandas, Matplotlib, Template matching using TM_SQDIFF, Random Forest, ANN

Comparing the performance of Machine Learning algorithms on Heart Disease Prediction

• This project is about identifying the best model (in Support Vector Machine, Naïve Bayes, Decision Tree) that suits for predicting heart disease.

Customer Satisfaction Analysis using Qualtrics and Tableau

- To evaluate customer feedback data to find areas for improvement in the customer experience journey, and to develop a dashboard using Tableau to track customer satisfaction levels.
- Tools and Technologies: Python, Tableau, SQL, MS Excel.